Aladdin Company Records Collection 1907-1989 (bulk 1940-1982)
Clarke Historical Library
Aladdin Company Records Collection 1907-1989 (bulk 1940-1982)
Aladdin Company.
approximately 350 cubic feet in 259 containers
MSS.
The collection documents the activities of the Aladdin Company and its founding family, the Sovereigns, from 1907 until 1989. The Aladdin Company was a manufacturer of catalog "kit homes" in Bay City, MI second in sales volume only to Sears Roebuck & Company. The collection includes company records, sales records (including building projects as part of WWI and WWII war efforts), Aladdin Company advertising materials, order and construction information, and personal records of various members of the Sovereign family - including the court records of the William Sovereign v. Mary Sovereign divorce case.
Clarke Historical Library, Central Michigan University
No Acc#
Aladdin Company Collection is open for research.
The Aladdin Company was founded as the North American Construction Company in 1906 by two brothers, William J. Sovereign and Otto E. Sovereign. William was a lawyer while Otto was an advertising man. The company was one of the earliest and longest-lived manufacturers of catalog (“Readi-cut”) houses. Although second in sales volume to the better-known Sears Roebuck & Company “kit homes,” Aladdin (as it became officially known in 1916) entered the business before Sears and remained in it some forty years after the last Sears home was sold.
Aladdin’s primary product was single family dwellings. The firm, however, also sold other products. As early as 1914 and as late as the 1960’s the firm sold house furnishings through prepared catalogs. An Aladdin trailer was introduced in 1934 and an expandable “Pullman Home” (a sort of modular house) in 1937. Neither the trailer or the modular home, however, were long lived. Throughout its history the firm was also involved in real estate speculation, usually involving relatively small parcels of land in the Bay City area. However, in the 1920’s, the company built Aladdin City, a planned community in Florida. Aladdin City, however, became a victim of the depression-era slump in Florida’s economy.
Despite these efforts to diversity, Aladdin remained primarily a seller of homes. Thus the firm’s fortunes were closely tied to that of the housing industry and followed the trends of the national economy. It prospered during both world wars by supplying military camp buildings to the U.S. government and workers’ housing to key industries. The company was particularly proud of filling and order for 200 houses from the Austin Motor Company of Birmingham, England in 1917. Sales boomed after World War I and during the prosperous 1920s but slumped dramatically during the Depression. After World War II the firm resumed production of civilian homes in 1947 and during the post-war years Aladdin again experienced robust sales. Operating losses for 1958, 1959 and 1960, however, made it evident that a changing housing market demanded new approaches by Aladdin. The problem report completed in 1961 attempted to identify problems and solutions. The “Build-It-Yourself” (B-I-Y) System introduced in 1962 promoted “the best features of Readi-cut and Pre-fab construction” (an aim enunciated by William F. Sovereign in the stockholders’ meeting of December 15, 1961.)
Despite tentative changes such as more preassembled, prenailed components, business continued to decline. In the 1970’s the company was unable to meet the challenge of ‘stagflation’ (inflation combined with a stagnating economy) late in that decade. As a result the firm ceased production in 1982.
Aladdin was always a family-owned company based in Bay City, Michigan. At various times, it also operated mills in Portland, Oregon; Hattiesburg, Mississippi; and Wilmington, North Carolina. The company enjoyed remarkable continuity of management; the founders remained in control until mid-century, Otto (Vice President, Treasurer and General Manager) died in 1954 and William J. (President) in 1968. William’s son, William F. Sovereign became president following his father’s death on June 5 1968, although he had been the defacto executive officer for some time. He continued to serve as president until the firm closed its doors.
The collection, approximately 350 cubic feet in 259 containers, is organized into eleven series. Some series are organized into sub-series as appropriate.
The Aladdin Company records, approximately 350 cubic feet, were discovered in a very disorganized state in 1994. Found in an abandoned Bay City warehouse, virtually the entire collection suffered from mold and mildew infestations, and in some cases water and mold had damaged items beyond repair. Only the films, architectural drawings and plans had remained largely intact and in their original filing order. Most of the company’s other records had become disorganized. A few records were found in file cabinets while others were in rolling vaults, the combinations for which had been lost. Boxes of material lay scattered in various locations, and much paper simply had come to rest on the floor.
Because of the condition the records were found in, most of the collection’s order has been imposed upon the records. Most, but not all, of the collection has also been fumigated. The collection is generally organized according to record type or major functions within the company. In addition, some miscellaneous groups of material have been placed at the end of the collection.
The collection is organized into eleven series: Corporate, Financial, Advertising, Order Department, Construction, Shipping Bills, Suppliers Transit & Mill Sites, Sovereign Family, Photographs and Films, Books and Magazines, and Miscellaneous.
The collection includes incorporation papers, directors’ meeting minutes, contracts, stock records and other basic corporate information, office manuals and procedures, studies, financial statements, appraisals, inventories, payroll, catalogs, advertising material, publications, art work, floor and construction plans, orders, billing lists, invoices, mailing lists, price bills, real estate records, personal records of the Sovereign family (including court records), photographs, films, magazines, and books.
Subjects:
Aladdin Company.; Prefabricated houses--Catalogs.; Architecture, Domestic--Designs and plans Catalogs.
- Aladdin Company Collection - Series #1, Corporate Records (Corporate and Administrative Records, 1909-1987)
  - Records, Incorporation Records,1909-1977 (Box 1, Folder 333)
  - Records, Secretary’s Record Book (Board of Director and Stockholder meetings),1909-1916 (Box 1, Folder 334)
  - Records, Secretary Records (Board of Director and Stockholder meetings),1917-1939 (Box 1, Folder 335)
  - Records, Secretary Records (Board of Director and Stockholder meetings), model house at 1401 Dean Street, Bay City (Hollywood 3),and property at 15 West Sharlear Street, Essexville,1940-1964 (Box 1, Folder 336)
  - Records, Stock, Summary of stock holders,1917-1975 (Box 1, Folder 337)
  - Records, Stock, Decreases in,1939,1966 (Box 1, Folder 338)
  - Records, Stock Books (2 books and some blank shares),1916-1975 (Box 1, Folder 339)
  - Records, Agreements between O.E. Sovereign, W.J. Sovereign and the Aladdin Co. re. compensation and stock ownership,1915-1929 (Box 1, Folder 340)
  - Records, Michigan Corporation annual reports and “Notice of Delinquency”,1950-1985, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 341)
  - Records, Registered Office or Registered Agent changes,1939-1977 (Box 1, Folder 342)
  - Records, Foreign Corporation Withdrawal Certificates (North Carolina, 1932 and 1954 and Oregon, 1939) and Aladdin Trailers Corporation dissolution,1939-1954 (Box 1, Folder 343)
  - Records, Trademark Registrations,1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 344)
- Aladdin Company Collection - Series #1, Administrative Records (Corporate and Administrative Records, 1909-1987)
  - Records, Aladdin Homes LTD – Canada,1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 350)
  - Records, Customer Surveys, Sales Summary & Salesmen Reports (5 folders),1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 345)
  - Records, Customer Surveys, Sales Summary & Salesmen Reports (5 folders),1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 346)
  - Records, Customer Surveys, Sales Summary & Salesmen Reports (5 folders),1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 347)
  - Records, Customer Surveys, Sales Summary & Salesmen Reports (5 folders),1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 348)
  - Records, Customer Surveys, Sales Summary & Salesmen Reports (5 folders),1950-1980 (Box 1, Folder 349)
  - Records, Company History,undated (Box 1, Folder 351)
  - Records, Co-operator in Marshfield, MA (2 folders original and use copies),1913-1922 (Box 1, Folder 352)
  - Records, Co-operator in Marshfield, MA (2 folders original and use copies),1913-1922 (Box 1, Folder 353)
  - Records, Co-operators,1915, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 354)
  - Records, Acquisition offer,1970 (Box 2, Folder 355)
  - Records, Administrative correspondence,1947-1954, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 356)
  - Records, Administrative correspondence,1947-1954, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 357)
  - Records, Advertising correspondence,1954-1958 (Box 2, Folder 358)
  - Records, Aladdin City - Florida,1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 359)
  - Records, Aladdin City - Florida,1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 360)
  - Records, Aladdin City - Florida,1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 361)
  - Records, Business correspondence – supplies, employment,1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 362)
  - Records, Business solicitation,1949-1958 (Box 2, Folder 363)
  - Records, Catalog mailing list, Sample cards,1981 (Box 2, Folder 364)
  - Records, Catalog requests,1926-1955 (Box 2, Folder 365)
  - Records, Catalog requests, Alaska & Hawaii,1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 366)
  - Records, Catalog requests, foreign,1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 367)
  - Records, Complaints (scattered),1923-1980 (Box 2, Folder 368)
  - Records, Complaints re Taylor-Mitchell (old dealer), Portsmouth, OH,1941 (Box 2, Folder 369)
  - Records, Complaints – Jesse Brown file,1965 (Box 2, Folder 370)
  - Records, Construction and Transportation,1947-1963 (Box 2, Folder 371)
  - Records, Consultant re. Post-World War II Resumption of Production,1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 372)
  - Records, Czech Project, Bert Zenaty,1927 (Box 3, Folder 373)
  - Records, Dealer and Importer/Exporter correspondence,1944-1967 (Box 3, Folder 374)
  - Records, Dog Houses,1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 375)
  - Records, Latter Day Saints church project – Evart, Michigan,1970, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 376)
  - Records, Miscellaneous, 1907-1972 – A. I. Lamb replaced by W. F. Sovereign as V.P. 1959, Hannah Sovereign Schust re. business strat., 1960,1907-1972 (Box 3, Folder 377)
  - Records, Miscellaneous customer correspondence,1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 378)
  - Records, Preliminary Orders, Alaska and Hawaii,undated (Box 3, Folder 379)
  - Records, Preliminary Orders, Foreign,1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 380)
  - Records, Radio Broadcast mentioning Aladdin,1940 (Box 3, Folder 381)
  - Records, Referral letters,1961-1976 (Box 3, Folder 382)
  - Records, Requests for parts replacements,1957-1982 (Box 3, Folder 383)
  - Records, Testimonials,1940-1981 (Box 3, Folder 384)
  - Records, Testimonials for 1950 catalog “Generation”,1950 (Box 3, Folder 385)
  - Records, War Contract correspondence,1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 386)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - standardized replies to customers (4 folders),1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 387)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - standardized replies to customers (4 folders),1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 388)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - standardized replies to customers (4 folders),1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 389)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - standardized replies to customers (4 folders),1922-1929 (Box 3, Folder 390)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 391)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 392)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 393)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 394)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 395)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 396)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 397)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 398)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 399)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 400)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 401)
  - Records, Form paragraphs - cont. (12 folders),1930-1972 (Box 4, Folder 402)
  - Records, Credit Reports, Dun-Bradstreet,1958, 1971-1983 (Box 4, Folder 403)
  - Records, Dealers, historical notes, agreement forms, equipment checking list, territories (2 folders),1941 (Box 4, Folder 404)
  - Records, Dealers, historical notes, agreement forms, equipment checking list, territories (2 folders),1941 (Box 4, Folder 405)
  - Records, Resignations - Senior officers,1910 (Box 4, Folder 406)
  - Records, Union agreement, pension plans, annual reports (1973-1974, 1974-1975), Mill employees (1951),1951, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 407)
  - Records, Trade Union correspondence,undated (Box 4, Folder 408)
  - Records, Union grievances,undated (Box 4, Folder 409)
  - Records, Two letters re. Portland, OR plant,1946 (Box 4, Folder 410)
  - Records, Union membership,1967-1981 (Box 4, Folder 411)
  - Records, Hours worked/month-union,1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 412)
  - Records, Salaries (1954-62), wage rates (1973),1954-1973 (Box 4, Folder 413)
  - Records, Hours & wages-mill (very incomplete),1963-1976 (Box 4, Folder 414)
  - Records, Pay scale - (1951-1961, 1967-1981). Mill rate increases (1962-1969),1951-1981 (Box 4, Folder 415)
  - Records, MISSING: Weekly wage rates & payroll changes-office (incomplete),1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 415a)
  - Records, MISSING: Memos re Pay raises & pay rates (1957, 1965-1980),1957-1980 (Box 4, Folder 415b)
  - Records, MISSING: Pay advances & loans,1969-1979 (Box 4, Folder 415c)
  - Records, Pay and union contract memos, grievances (1961-1962;1971-1972),1961-1962, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 416)
  - Records, Michigan Mutual Insurance Company,undated (Box 4, Folder 417)
  - Records, Minors,1961, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 418)
  - Records, Pension Plans,undated (Box 4, Folder 419)
  - Records, Injuries (3 folders),1962-1964, 1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 420)
  - Records, Injuries (3 folders),1962-1964, 1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 421)
  - Records, Injuries (3 folders),1962-1964, 1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 422)
  - Records, Occupational Safety and Health Administration/Record-keeping requirements,undated (Box 5, Folder 423)
  - Records, Retirements & separations (samples),1966-1981 (Box 5, Folder 424)
  - Records, MISSING: Turkey lists,1968-1979 (Box 5, Folder 424a)
  - Records, Vacation pay (1963-1981), Manuscript rules for same, Union seniority lists (1963, 1966, 1981),1963-1981 (Box 5, Folder 425)
  - Records, Bonuses,1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 426)
  - Records, Job application-office,1954, 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 427)
  - Records, Employee fraud - New York,1919-1923 (Box 5, Folder 428)
  - Records, Sales meetings,1958-1959, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 429)
  - Records, Company meeting notes: May 25, 1960,1960 (Box 5, Folder 430)
  - Records, Orders listed by salesman,1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 431)
  - Records, Number of customer visits by month,1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 432)
  - Records, Salesmen Reports (3 folders),1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 433)
  - Records, Salesmen Reports (3 folders),1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 434)
  - Records, Salesmen Reports (3 folders),1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 435)
  - Records, Aladdin government contracts,1942 (Box 5, Folder 436)
  - Records, Aladdin Co. barracks building, 20’ x 100’,undated (Box 5, Folder 437)
  - Records, Aladdin Co. bunk house prices and specifications,1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 438)
  - Records, Correspondence and memos (interoffice),1942 (Box 5, Folder 439)
  - Records, Aladdin Company demountable barracks. 20’ x 48’3 ¼ ‘. Prefab & readi-cut specifications and blueprints,1943 (Box 5, Folder 440)
  - Records, Aladdin Company demountable home. 26’5 ¼ ‘ x 20’. Drawings,1942 (Box 5, Folder 441)
  - Records, Aladdin Company lumber orders,1942 (Box 5, Folder 442)
  - Records, Aladdin Company material requirements on various contracts,1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 443)
  - Records, Aladdin Company contracts1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 444)
  - Records, Aladdin Company pit latrines, scrub deck, showers,1943 (Box 5, Folder 445)
  - Records, Aladdin Company prefabricated barracks. Brochures/ price list,1943 (Box 5, Folder 446)
  - Records, Aladdin Company qualification record, 22 April 1942/ List of Gov. and Industrial Projects 1917 start,1917,1942 (Box 5, Folder 447)
  - Records, Aladdin Company quantity orders. Comprehensive list including individuals,1914-1945 (Box 5, Folder 448)
  - Records, Army Air Corps Order File,1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 449)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company - Birmingham, England. Records re. order of 200 houses. (4 folders, two folders of original material, two folders of copies),1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 450)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company - Birmingham, England. Records re. order of 200 houses. (4 folders, two folders of original material, two folders of copies),1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 451)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company - Birmingham, England. Records re. order of 200 houses. (4 folders, two folders of original material, two folders of copies),1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 452)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company - Birmingham, England. Records re. order of 200 houses. (4 folders, two folders of original material, two folders of copies),1916-1917 (Box 5, Folder 453)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company contract and specifications,undated (Box 5, Folder 454)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company bills of materials for special Chester,1917,1922 (Box 5, Folder 455)
  - Records, Austin Motor Company - Birmingham, England, letter re: 200 Aladdin homes sold to Austin in 1917,1944 (Box 5, Folder 456)
  - Records, Bechtel, Price, Callahan; Edmonton, Alberta, Canada - 20 x 100 buildings,1943 (Box 6, Folder 457)
  - Records, Bechtel, Price, Callahan; Edmonton, Alberta, Canada - Barracks, Portland mill,1943 (Box 6, Folder 458)
  - Records, Bechtel, Price, Callahan; Edmonton, Alberta, Canada - Barracks #23105,1943 (Box 6, Folder 459)
  - Records, Buick; General Motors Corporation - Flint, MI. Airplane engine shipping cases,1941 (Box 6, Folder 460)
  - Records, Charleston Shipbuilding & Drydock Company - Charleston, S.C. CCC building, Specs. #38783,undated (Box 6, Folder 461)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Shipping to Tacoma, WA,1942 (Box 6, Folder 462)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Estimates and figures,1942 (Box 6, Folder 463)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Prices, material,1942 (Box 6, Folder 464)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Painting,1942 (Box 6, Folder 465)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Quoting for Major Heiss (Columbus, OH),1942 (Box 6, Folder 466)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Quoting for Major Heiss - 43 Demountable buildings,1942 (Box 6, Folder 467)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Books with price lists,1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 468)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Material Purchases (2 books),1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 469)
  - Records, CCC buildings. To ship from Portland, OR,1942 (Box 6, Folder 470)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Material price list and panel labor time, hardware, veneer,1943 (Box 6, Folder 471)
  - Records, CCC buildings. Plan 265. Smoke jacks. Tacoma, WA also prefab mobile depot group barracks - CCC type,1940-1950 (Box 6, Folder 472)
  - Records, Central Steel Tube Company - Clinton, Iowa,1941 (Box 6, Folder 473)
  - Records, Continental Motor Car Company - Muskegon, MI. Airplane,undated (Box 6, Folder 474)
  - Records, Engine boxes,1941 (Box 6, Folder 475)
  - Records, Co-operative Society of Reykjavik, Iceland, #38555,1941 (Box 6, Folder 476)
  - Records, Defense Plant Corporation - Washington D.C. 20’x100’ steel warehouse bid,1944 (Box 6, Folder 477)
  - Records, Emergency Fleet Corporation Housing,1918 (Box 6, Folder 478)
  - Records, Fort Brady - Sault Ste. Marie, MI; Lumber pricing. Blueprints,1942 (Box 7, Folder 478a)
  - Records, Fort Brady - Sault Ste. Marie, MI; Pricing basis and change orders,1942 (Box 7, Folder 479)
  - Records, Fort Brady - Sault Ste. Marie, MI,1942 (Box 7, Folder 480)
  - Records, Fort Myer, VA,1917 (Box 7, Folder 481)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contract, other documents, correspondence,1917 (Box 7, Folder 482)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contracts, boarding, heater fdtns., teams (horses),1917 (Box 7, Folder 483)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contracts, concrete & plumbing, hardware list,1917 (Box 7, Folder 484)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Chicago plumbing list,1917 (Box 7, Folder 485)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contract, electrical,1917 (Box 7, Folder 486)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contracts, lumber,1917 (Box 7, Folder 487)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Contract, sewer & water,1917 (Box 7, Folder 488)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Correspondence,1917 (Box 7, Folder 489)
  - Records, Fort Snelling, MN. Statements of expenditure,1917 (Box 7, Folder 490)
  - Records, Frigidaire Divison, GM Corporation - Dayton OH; Boxes for 50 cal. machine guns,1941 (Box 7, Folder 491)
  - Records, Georgia Hardware Lumber Company, Export House, December 15,1944 (Box 7, Folder 492)
  - Records, Gerholtz Healy Company - Flint, MI; Houses in Flint, Ann Arbor, Lansing,1941 (Box 7, Folder 493)
  - Records, Government job bids/ List of bidders,1917 (Box 7, Folder 494)
  - Records, Grain bins; blueprints, drawings,1942 (Box 7, Folder 495)
  - Records, Grain bins; correspondence, specifications, bills of material,1942 (Box 7, Folder 496)
  - Records, Grain bins; initial letter from M.B. Kolb Co., specifications, figures,1942 (Box 7, Folder 497)
  - Records, Grain bins; correspondence,1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 498)
  - Records, Grain bins; government specifications, drawings,1950 (Box 7, Folder 499)
  - Records, Granse, Herman vs the Aladdin Company (2 folders),1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 500)
  - Records, Granse, Herman vs the Aladdin Company (2 folders),1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 501)
  - Records, Granse, Herman vs the Aladdin Company (c. 1944-1947), Papers of Judge Clark (26 February 1947),1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 502)
  - Records, Granse, Herman vs the Aladdin Company (c. 1944-1947), Letter to Judge Clark from W.J. Sovereign (26 May 1947): Granse’s pay under Payroll Act,1944-1947 (Box 7, Folder 503)
  - Records, Granse, Herman vs the Aladdin Company settlement,1947, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 504)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA; Readi-cut bunkhouse 10’x20’,1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 505)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA; Bunkhouses - 3 Minnesota style, #38612-13-14 - Shelby, MI,1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 506)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA; Bunkhouses - 2 Minnesota style, #38615-16 - Fremont, MI,1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 507)
  - Records, H.J.Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA. Bunkhouses - 5 Minnesota style; 2 to Zeeland, MI - #38617-18, 3 to Mecosta, MI - #38619-20-21,1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 508)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA. Bunkhouses - 25 Minnesota style to Wild Rose, WI - #38622-38646,1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 509)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA. Boxes and pallet boards,1944 (Box 8, Folder 510)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA,1945 (Box 8, Folder 511)
  - Records, H.J. Heinz Company - Pittsburgh, PA (1943, 1944, 1948(letter)). Correspondence, White order sheets for 38705-38729, 38747-38749, 38750-39771, 38732-38746, 38778, 38779-38782, 38772-38773, 38774-38777 (1944), Misc. related material (bunkhouse),1943-1948 (Box 8, Folder 512)